<resources>
    <string name="app_name">scalablescrollview</string>

    <string name="android_article">
        From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia
        \n
        \n
        Jump to navigationJump to search
        For other uses, see Android (disambiguation).
        Android
        Android logo (2014).svg
        Screenshot
        Developer
        Google,
        Open Handset Alliance
        Written in	Java (UI), C (core), C++ and others[1]
        OS family	Unix-like (Modified Linux kernel)
        Working state	Current
        Source model	Open source (most devices include proprietary components, such as Google Play)
        Initial release	September 23, 2008; 10 years ago[2]
        Latest release	9.0 "Pie" / August 6, 2018; 10 months ago
        Latest preview	Android Q Beta 4 (QPP4.190502.018)[3] / June 5, 2019; 2 days ago
        Marketing target	Smartphones, tablet computers, smartTVs (Android TV), Android Auto and smartwatches (Wear OS)
        Available in	100+ languages[4]
        Update method	Over-the-air
        Package manager	APK (primarily through Google Play; installation of APKs also possible locally or from alternative sources such as F-Droid)
        Platforms	32- and 64-bit ARM, x86 and x86-64
        Kernel type	Monolithic
        Userland	Bionic libc,[5] mksh shell,[6] Toybox as core utilities (beginning with Android 6.0)[7][8]
        Default user interface	Graphical (multi-touch)
        License
        Apache License 2.0
        GNU GPL v2 for the Linux kernel modifications[9]
        Official website	www.android.com
        Articles in the series
        Android version history
        Android is a mobile operating system developed by Google. It is based on a modified version of the Linux kernel and other open source software, and is designed primarily for touchscreen mobile devices such as smartphones and tablets. In addition, Google has developed Android TV for televisions, Android Auto for cars, and Wear OS for wrist watches, each with a specialized user interface. Variants of Android are also used on game consoles, digital cameras, PCs and other electronics.

        Initially developed by Android Inc., which Google bought in 2005, Android was unveiled in 2007, with the first commercial Android device launched in September 2008. The current stable version is Android 9 "Pie", released in August 2018. Google released the first beta of the next release, Android Q, on Pixel phones in March 2019. The core Android source code is known as Android Open Source Project (AOSP), which is primarily licensed under the Apache License.

        Android is also associated with a suite of proprietary software developed by Google, called Google Mobile Services (GMS),[10] that frequently comes pre-installed on devices. This includes core apps such as Gmail, the application store/digital distribution platform Google Play and associated Google Play Services development platform, and usually includes the Google Chrome web browser and Google Search app. These apps are licensed by manufacturers of Android devices certified under standards imposed by Google, but AOSP has been used as the basis of competing Android ecosystems such as Amazon.com\'s Fire OS, which use their own equivalents to Google Mobile Services.

        Android has been the best-selling OS worldwide on smartphones since 2011 and on tablets since 2013. As of May 2017, it has over two billion monthly active users, the largest installed base of any operating system, and as of December 2018, the Google Play store features over 2.6 million apps
    </string>
</resources>
